<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Variables on R tutorials for macroecology</title>
    <link>/tags/variables/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Variables on R tutorials for macroecology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/variables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroecological analysis at the species level</title>
      <link>/2018/02/06/species-level-macroecological-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/06/species-level-macroecological-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I have shown how to use letsR to analyze species traits at the community level. But, in many cases this type of analysis can lead to spurious patterns (click here for further discussion on this issue). An alternative can be analyzing the data at the species-level. In this post, I will show two examples on how to make macroecological analysis at the species level using the letsR package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping species traits</title>
      <link>/2018/01/30/mapping-species-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/30/mapping-species-traits/</guid>
      <description>Many times scientists are interested in analyzing or describing the geographical variation of a trait. For example, how species body size varies across the space. Here I will show how to map species traits using the letsR package.
To do this, let’s test the Rapoport’s rule on Phyllomedusa frogs. Following Wikipedia: “Rapoport’s rule is an ecogeographical rule that states that latitudinal ranges of plants and animals are generally smaller at lower latitudes than at higher latitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding variables to a PresenceAbsence object</title>
      <link>/2018/01/26/adding-variables-to-a-presenceabsence-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/26/adding-variables-to-a-presenceabsence-object/</guid>
      <description>Once you have transformed species distribution data into a presence absence matrix (PAM) in PresenceAbsence format (see the first and second posts on how to do it), you may want to add variables to it. These variables are normally in raster format, for example the WorldClim bioclimatic data, or in shapefile format, for example ecorregions of the world.
Adding variables in raster format To add variables in raster format to a PresenceAbsence object we can use the function lets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>