<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Letsr on R tutorials for macroecology</title>
    <link>/tags/letsr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Letsr on R tutorials for macroecology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/letsr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phylogenetic and spatial autocorrelogram</title>
      <link>/2018/03/07/phylogenetic-and-spatial-autocorrelogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/07/phylogenetic-and-spatial-autocorrelogram/</guid>
      <description>https://www.cs.princeton.edu/picasso/mats/PCA-Tutorial-Intuition_jp.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping plants phylogenetic diversity</title>
      <link>/2018/02/12/mapping-plant-richness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/12/mapping-plant-richness/</guid>
      <description>Retrieving plant species distributions from R has recently become quite easy using the BIEN R package, which facilitates the access to the Botanical Information and Ecology Network database. In addition to plant distributions, BIEN allow users to also obtain traits and phylogenetic plant data, making it a resourceful tool for macroecologists. Here I will show how to integrate BIEN and letsR to map phylogenetic diversity, using as an example the Pinus species of North America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroecological analysis at the species level</title>
      <link>/2018/02/06/species-level-macroecological-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/06/species-level-macroecological-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I have shown how to use letsR to analyze species traits at the community level. But, in many cases this type of analysis can lead to spurious patterns (click here for further discussion on this issue). An alternative can be analyzing the data at the species-level. In this post, I will show two examples on how to make macroecological analysis at the species level using the letsR package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping species traits</title>
      <link>/2018/01/30/mapping-species-traits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/30/mapping-species-traits/</guid>
      <description>Many times scientists are interested in analyzing or describing the geographical variation of a trait. For example, how species body size varies across the space. Here I will show how to map species traits using the letsR package.
To do this, let’s test the Rapoport’s rule on Phyllomedusa frogs. Following Wikipedia: “Rapoport’s rule is an ecogeographical rule that states that latitudinal ranges of plants and animals are generally smaller at lower latitudes than at higher latitudes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding variables to a PresenceAbsence object</title>
      <link>/2018/01/26/adding-variables-to-a-presenceabsence-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/26/adding-variables-to-a-presenceabsence-object/</guid>
      <description>Once you have transformed species distribution data into a presence absence matrix (PAM) in PresenceAbsence format (see the first and second posts on how to do it), you may want to add variables to it. These variables are normally in raster format, for example the WorldClim bioclimatic data, or in shapefile format, for example ecorregions of the world.
Adding variables in raster format To add variables in raster format to a PresenceAbsence object we can use the function lets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cropping and subseting your presence absence matrix</title>
      <link>/2018/01/24/cropping-and-subseting-your-presence-absence-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/24/cropping-and-subseting-your-presence-absence-matrix/</guid>
      <description>In previous posts I showed how to build a presence absence matrix (PAM) from species distribution data (check here) as PresenceAbsence object (check also how to transform a PAM into a PresenceAbsence). In this post I will show how to subset or crop a PresenceAbsence object.
Subseting a PresenceAbsence object can be done using the function lets.subsetPAM. You just need to provide the species you want to keep, and the PresenceAbsence object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfom a matrix of species presence absence into a PresenceAbsence object</title>
      <link>/2018/01/24/transfom-a-matrix-of-species-presence-absence-into-a-presenceabsence-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/24/transfom-a-matrix-of-species-presence-absence-into-a-presenceabsence-object/</guid>
      <description>Most of letsR package functions require a PresenceAbsence object (see previous post). But some users may already have a matrix of species presence absence (PAM) generated somewhere else or created using the lets.presab.grid function. In this post I will show how to transform these PAM files into a PresenceAbsence object.
First, note that this will only be possible if your grid used to generate the PAM is a square or a rectangular grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to transform species distributions into a presence absence matrix based on a user-defined grid in R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/23/a-guide-to-transform-species-shapefiles-into-a-presence-absence-matrix-based-on-a-user-defined-grid-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/23/a-guide-to-transform-species-shapefiles-into-a-presence-absence-matrix-based-on-a-user-defined-grid-system/</guid>
      <description>Species distribution are largely available in online databases, such as the distributions ranges in IUCN, or the occurrence records in GBIF. However, to analyze these kind of data most of the time it is necessary to transform the spatial distribution of species into a presence absence matrix or into a grid format. In this tutorial I will show how to easily make this transformation using the R package letsR, written by myself and Fabricio Villalobos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>